Protecting the crown. Minding the children.
The Royal Nanny is a tv movie, comedy, drama film directed by Jonathan Wright.
Claire is an MI5 agent who goes undercover as the royal nanny.
She must overcome the challenges of her assignment, like resisting the charms
of Prince Colin, while keeping the family safe at Christmas.
Claire Champion, played by Rachel Skarsten.
Prince Colin, played by Dan Jeannotte.
Ms. Juliet Lansbury, played by Greta Scacchi.
Wallace, played by Toussaint Meghie.
Princess Rose, played by Katie Sheridan.
Vance, played by Martin Swabey.
A nanny is a person who provides child care.
Typically, this care is given within the children's family setting.
Throughout history, nannies were usually servants in large
households and reported directly to the lady of the house.
Today, modern nannies, like other domestic workers, may live in or out of the
house, depending on their circumstances and those of their employers.
Some employment agencies specialize in providing nannies, as there are families that
specifically seek them and may make them a part of the household.
Nannies differ slightly from other child care providers.
A childminder works out of their own home, operating as a small business.
In America, childminders are often advertised as a daycare.
Depending on the country the childminder or daycare is in,
government registration may or may not be required.
Within the UK, a childminder must be Ofsted-registered, hold a current pediatric
first aid qualification, public liability insurance and follow the EYFS.
A mother's helper is someone who may live in or out of the household, and assists the
person of the house with general chores as well as caring for the children.
The term au pair usually refers to a young person, who comes from abroad to live with the host
family and learn the local culture and language, while helping care for the children.
A governess concentrates on educating children inside their own home, and a
kindergarten or schoolteacher does the same, but in a school environment.
Even though there are no legal requirements to be considered a nanny,
families may require a background check and a CPR certification.
Families may also look for other special skills in a nanny, such as being
bilingual or having early childhood development coursework done.
Nannies help play a key role in a child's development by providing care.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.